Leichhardt N.S.W. 2040 Australia Mobile: +61 448 366 061 Email: ryan@ryant.org

Profile

I draw my expertise from a diverse range of experience in both software and non-software related roles. My technical background is primarily the development and operation of large-scale distributed systems, people management, and setting the strategic direction for development groups.

- Strong knowledge of distributed systems and their fundamentals.
- Demonstrated ability to manage multiple projects simultaneously.
- Technically minded with the ability to quickly adapt to an ever changing environment.
- Strong leader with a track record for growing impactful teams.

Skills and Technical Experience

Languages: Java, Rust, Go, SQL

Cloud Providers: GCP, AWS

Operating Systems: Linux, OS X, Windows

Vehicle Licences: MR (Medium Rigid), R (Motorcycle), PPL(A) (Private Pilot, Fixed Wing)

Professional Experience

Microsoft, Australia Head of Production, Reliability, and Security Engineering — Australia January 2020 — Current

Heading up the Azure PRSE group in Australia, building out the Australian engineering presence as well as the SRE and Incident Management capabilities.

Google, Australia Engineering Manager — Accelerated Storage SRE November 2017 — January 2020

The Accelerated Storage SRE team is responsible for building and managing a number of high-throughput, low-latency systems critical to the success of the business. My role was to grow out the team in Sydney, and along with our sister team in Seattle set and drive strategic programs of work, as well as technical growth in the team members.

Google, Ireland Technical Program Manager — Search SRE October 2014 — November 2017

As a part of the Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) group my focus was driving strategic projects for the Google Search team.

This role involved leading the global program management group for Search SRE across Dublin, Zurich and Mountain View and setting the strategic direction in collaboration with other engineering leaders for Search and the underlying production infrastructure.

Ryan Thomas

Atlassian, Sydney, N.S.W. Engineering Manager December 2009 — October 2014

Leading multiple teams, I have taken on many challenging projects and have been able to deliver on time and without cutting scope.

The projects have generally been in the area of how Atlassian delivers software to its hosted platform, and most recently an ongoing project to develop and deliver an internal PaaS for hosting and deploying services inside of Atlassian.

This role has required me to manage engineering resources, liaise with project stakeholders, set (& reset) project goals and present justification of the projects to executives.

Objective Corporation Limited, North Sydney, N.S.W. Software Engineer / Enterprise Search Specialist August 2009 — December 2009

My role at Objective Corporation was to take ownership of the search and indexing services of the Objective Software Suite and provide guidance and support for the current and future implementations. These services utilise Verity's K2 search server and I was tasked with investigating and prototyping a replacement; with Apache Solr being the selected at the time.

Australian Defence Force — Army Trainee Pilot March 2008 — June 2009

I have completed the Australian Defence Force Basic Pilots Course and Army Intermediate Pilots Course and hold a military endorsement for the PAC CT-4B aircraft for day and night operations.

The training I have received during my time as an officer in the Army has given me experience in the management of personnel on the ground, in a multi-crew airborne environment and in the making of time critical decisions.

Oracle Corporation, North Ryde, N.S.W. Senior Software Engineer March 2007 — March 2008

Hyperion Solutions, North Sydney, N.S.W. Software Engineer
December 2005 — March 2007

TransActive Systems, Gosford, N.S.W. Software Developer / Technical Support July 2004 — December 2005

BAE Systems, Williamtown, N.S.W. Software Developer (intern)
July — September 2003

Qualifications

Master of Science (Computer Science)

Georgia Institute of Technology. 2017 — Current Georgia, United States of America

Certificate of Advanced Project Managment

Stanford. 2015 - 2016 California, United States of America

Bachelor of Engineering — Software Engineering

The University of Newcastle. 2001 — 2005 New South Wales, Australia

Certificate III — Resource Operations

Australian Army, September 2005

Certificate III — Business (Frontline Management)

Australian Army, September 2005

Certificate III — Government

Australian Army, September 2005

Certificate III — Transport & Distribution (Road Transport)

Australian Army, April 2002

Higher School Certificate

Corpus Christi College, Tuggerah. 1999 — 2000

Professional Credentials

Professional Member

Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) 2005 - 2012

Bombardier

Royal Australian Artillery, Australian Army Reserve2000-2010

Referees

Available on request.